{
    "id": "90943c28680a451c97a01bad2dbb1548",
    "title": "Relative Pronouns Worksheet",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "He stole the bike ……………………….. belonged to his neighbor.",
            "description": "Which is used to refer to things. That can also refer to things in identifying relative clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "26828ac4c0bd4fcc8a9d2fb0a80568ad"
        },
        {
            "question": "I have no money …………………….. I can lend you.",
            "description": "That can refer to both people and things. It is more common than which after words like no, all, any etc. ",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "19f89e4185aa4e50b9bcda4cfb8bf69d"
        },
        {
            "question": "The dog ……………………….. I adopted from a shelter is my best friend now.",
            "description": "Which is used to refer to things. That can also refer to things in identifying relative clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "6754b6c8d5b1485981176f590b08b7f7"
        },
        {
            "question": "He lives in the same house ………………………….. he was born.",
            "description": "Where can mean in which.",
            "answers": [
                "where",
                "which",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7edf4b8329c142228b57111619fa75db"
        },
        {
            "question": "Those ………………………… are content do not need any wealth.",
            "description": "Who refers to people. ",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "whom",
                "which"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2f050ade00b14477b8e49c27d0deb98a"
        },
        {
            "question": "We met a girl …………………………… was carrying a flower basket on her head.",
            "description": "Who refers to people. It acts as the subject of the relative clause.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "which",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2c31d3c8e72e4ad791528af96b8ce8c5"
        },
        {
            "question": "The horse ………………………….. I bought the other day is lame.",
            "description": "Which is used to refer to things. That can also refer to things in identifying relative clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "2c03a5fd803346fd98363e8f43abb942"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t trust people …………………………. go back on their promises.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "which",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1ef9c818822242a7920710edd84ec7ac"
        },
        {
            "question": "I talked to the young girl ………………………… looked worried.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "she",
                "whom"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c50bd9f0a1964e068ec5e7af2ed730b5"
        },
        {
            "question": "I lost the watch ………………………… I bought last week.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "that",
                "which",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0d844fdd375e4617a669147bcab88391"
        },
        {
            "question": "The castle …………………………. stands on that hill was built in the 16th century.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "which",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "e9d05162298c44348b4f731c7831ee34"
        },
        {
            "question": "A man ………………………… is loyal will have many friends.",
            "description": "In identifying relative clauses both who and that can refer to people.",
            "answers": [
                "who",
                "that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "0623d700ee8b4133b9f567fbcad583be"
        }
    ]
}